4ocean.com 2019-12-13

# Privacy Policy

Updated: July 20, 2018

Effective: May 24, 2018

Privacy Policy

At 4ocean, we take privacy very seriously and it is always our goal to communicate with our supporters in the most efficient and effective way while also protecting the sensitive personal information we collect. This statement of the privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) of 4ocean LLC, (“4ocean”) is intended to provide you the user (“YOU”) of the 4ocean Website located at www.4Ocean.com (“Website”) the following information:

1\. Information 4ocean Collects: What personally identifiable information of yours or third party personally identification is collected from you through the web site

2\. How We Use Your Information

3\. How We Share Your information

4\. With Whom the Information May Be Shared

5\. What Choices Are Available to You Regarding Collection, Use and Distribution of the Information

6\. The Kind of Security Procedures that are in Place to Protect the Loss, Misuse or Alteration of Information Under 4ocean's Control

7\. How You Can Correct Any Inaccuracies in the Information.

8\. Data Retention

9\. How to Contact Us

A. Information Collection

4ocean is the sole owner of the information collected on the 4ocean Website. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. We may also collect Personal Information about you when you interact with us on social media sites and from other third parties and may also automatically collect information that may contain Personal Information as described in 4ocean's Cookie Policy.  We may use that Personal Information where in our legitimate interest to do so for the following purposes: to contact you and respond to your requests and enquiries; to personalize your visit and use of our Internet Services and to assist you while you use those services; to carry out, monitor and analyze our business or website operations; and to contact you (unless you tell us that you prefer us not to) regarding publications, newsletters, cleanups and other events that may be of interest to you. If you do not want to receive publications or details of events that we consider may be of interest to you, you may do so by clicking on the unsubscribe link in electronic marketing communications. 

4ocean collects information from our users at several different points on our Website including:

  1. Account Information
  2. Payment Information
  3. Third Party Collections

B. Account Information

In order to purchase products from the Website, a user must first complete the registration form. During registration a user is required to give their contact information (such as name and email address). This information is used to contact the user about the products on our site for which they have expressed interest.

  1. Full Name
  2. Email Address
  3. Shipping Address
  4. Telephone Number (optional)

C. Payment Information

We require information from the user on our order form in order to process any purchases using a third-party partner. Here a user must provide contact information (like name and shipping address) and financial information (like credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill the customer’s orders. If we have trouble processing an order, this contact information is used to get in touch with the user.

  1. Billing Address
  2. Credit Card Type

D. Third Party Collections

We use Third Parties to collect and store our Account and Payment Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy as well as other information related to volunteer work and customer service.

  1. Shopify (this is the platform that technically collects and stores the information for all transactions through our checkout page)
  2. Authorize.net (this is the app that we use to collect the credit card information. It is accessed through Shopify but it technically is not Shopify)
  3. SpringBot (this is the platform that collects name and email address for marketing on-site through SpringBot forms)
  4. Formstack (this is the platform that we use to collect and house information for people who want to do cleanups both domestically and abroad)
  5. CookieBot (this is the app that we use to allow users in the EU who use our website, to fully manage their data including Erasure Rights)
  6. BazaarVoice (this is the platform that we use to allow unbiased, consumer generated reviews and ratings)

E. Cookies

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. Once the user closes their browser, the cookie simply terminates. For instance, by setting a cookie on our site, the user would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use our

site. The only drawback to this is that the user will be limited in some areas of our site. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site. Some of our business partners use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies.

For personal data subject to the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”), we rely on several legal bases to process the data. These include when you have given your consent, which you may withdraw at any time using your account settings; when the processing is necessary to perform a contract with you, like the Terms of Service; and our legitimate business interests, such as in improving, personalizing, and developing the Services, marketing new features or products that may be of interest, and promoting safety and security as in this Privacy Policy.

F. Log Files

We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

G. How We Use Your Information

We use the information we collect for the following purposes:

  1. To provide Services and Products
  2. To improve Services and Products (to the extent applicable)
  3. To deliver the Products and Services to you (for example, full name and shipping address)
  4. To improve the Services (for example, we use the information to troubleshoot, perform data analysis and testing and to develop new features)
  5. To share information about our Company (via our newsletter)
  6. To share information about new Products (via our newsletter)
  7. To share information about 4ocean events (via our newsletter)

H. How Your Information Is Shared

We will share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person.

We use an outside shipping company to ship orders and a credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes.

We partner with four other third parties, such as SpringBot, CookieBot, Bazaarvoice and Formstack to provide specific services. When the user signs up for these services, we will share names, or other contact information that is necessary for the third party to provide these services.

These parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services.

We may also share your information for legal reasons or to prevent harm. We may preserve or disclose information about you to comply with a law, regulation, legal process, or governmental request; to assert legal rights or defend against legal claims; or to prevent, detect, or investigate illegal activity, fraud, abuse, violations of our terms, or threats to the security of the Services.

If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of assets, we will continue to take measures to protect the confidentiality of personal information and give affected users notice before transferring any personal information to a new entity.

I. Links

This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we (4ocean) are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.

J. Newsletter

If a user wishes to subscribe to our newsletter, we ask for contact information such as name and email address.

K. Surveys & Contests

From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information.

Information requested may include contact information (such as name, email address and/or shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code, gender or age level). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site.

L. Tell-A-Friend

If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, we ask them for the friend’s name and email address. 4ocean will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the site.

4ocean stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email. The friend may contact us at [info@4Ocean.com](mailto:info@4Ocean.com) to request the removal of this information from our database.

M. Security

This website takes every precaution to protect our users’ information. When users submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and off-line. When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number), that information is

encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Google Chrome and Microsoft Internet

Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when you are just ‘surfing’. To learn more about SSL, follow this link: [Transport Layer Security](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transport_Layer_Security).

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users’ information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Our employees must use password-protected screen-savers when they leave their desk. When they return, they must re-enter their password to re-gain access to your information. Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Every quarter, as well as any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our customers’ information is protected.

Finally, the servers that we store personally identifiable information on are kept in a secure environment, behind a locked cage. If you have any questions about the security at our website, you can send an

email to [info@4Ocean.com](mailto:info@4Ocean.com).

N. Special Offers

New and established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and our newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see our choice and opt-out in letter Q below.

O. Site and Service Updates

We also send the user site and service announcement updates. Users are not able to un-subscribe from service announcements, which contain important information about the service. We communicate with the user to provide requested services and in regard to issues relating to their account via email or phone.

P. Your Rights to Access and Control Your Personal Data.

We give you access and control of your personal data as described in this Privacy Policy. If you live

in the European Economic Area, United Kingdom, and Switzerland (the “Designated Countries”), you

have a number of legal rights with respect to your information,

Q. Data Retention

We will retain your data for a period of 6 months from the time we first collect your data if you have no additional activity or until you opt out, whichever comes first. 

R. Policies for Children

In order to respect the privacy of minors, 4ocean does not knowingly collect, maintain or process Personal Information submitted online via our Internet Services by anyone under the age of 18. To the extent 4ocean collects Personal Information on minors in the context of one of the purposes mentioned in the Statement, 4ocean will only do so with the appropriate consent or as otherwise permitted under applicable laws.

S. Your California Privacy Rights

Under California Civil Code Section 1798.83, California customers are entitled to request information relating to whether a business has disclosed Personal Information to any third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. 4ocean does not sell or share your Personal Information with third-party companies for their direct marketing purposes without your consent.

T. International Data Transfers

We will rely on multiple legal bases to lawfully transfer personal data around the world. These include

your consent, the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield, and EU Commission approved model contractual clauses, which require certain privacy and security protections. You may obtain copies of the model contractual clauses by contacting us. 4ocean complies with the Privacy Shield principles regarding the collection, use, sharing, and retention of personal information as described in our Privacy Shield certifications.

4ocean is subject to the oversight of the US Federal Trade Commission and remains responsible for

personal information that we transfer to others who process it on our behalf as described in the How

Information Is Shared section. If you have a complaint about our Privacy Shield compliance,

please contact us. You can also refer a complaint to our chosen independent dispute resolution

body, the International Centre for Dispute Resolution® at [http://go.adr.org/privacyshield.html](http://go.adr.org/privacyshield.html).    

Please note that the countries where we operate may have privacy and data protection laws that

differ from, and are potentially less protective than, the laws of your country. You agree to this risk

when you create a 4ocean's account and click “I agree” to data transfers, irrespective of which

country you live in. If you later wish to withdraw your consent, you can delete your information as

described in the Privacy Policy.

You have the right to lodge a complaint regarding your information with the proper supervising authority.

U. Correction/Updating Personal Information:

If a user’s personally identifiable information changes (such as your zip code), or if a user no longer desires our service, we will endeavor to provide a way to correct, update or remove that user’s personal data provided to us. This can usually be done at the user account page or by emailing our Customer Support at info@4Ocean.com or by sending a written request to:

4ocean LLC,

Attention: Privacy Officer

6560 W. Rogers Circle

Suite 19

Boca Raton, FL 33487

P. Choice/Opt-out

Our users are given the opportunity to ‘opt-out’ of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our site at the point where we ask for the information. For example, our order form has an ‘opt-out’ mechanism so users who buy a product from us, but don’t want any marketing material, can keep their email address off of our lists.

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter or promotional materials from our partners may opt-out of receiving these communications by clicking the opt-out, unsubscribe button, or email us at info@4Ocean.com or by sending a written request to:

4ocean LLC,

Attention: Privacy Officer

6560 W. Rogers Circle

Suite 19

Boca Raton, FL 33487

P. Choice/Opt-out

Users of our site are always notified when their information is being collected by any outside parties. We do this, so our users can make an informed choice as to whether they should proceed with services that require an outside party, or not.

V. Notification of Changes

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on our Website, so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of an email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under

which the information was collected.

W. How to Contact Us

If you have questions, suggestions, or concerns about this policy, or about our use of your

information, please contact us at info@4Ocean.com or by sending a written request to:

4ocean LLC,

Attention: Privacy Officer

6560 W. Rogers Circle

Suite 19

Boca Raton, FL 33487

If you live in the European Economic Area, United Kingdom, or Switzerland and are seeking to exercise any of your statutory rights, please contact our Privacy Officer at info@4Ocean.com or by sending a written request to:

4ocean LLC,

Attention: Privacy Officer

6560 W. Rogers Circle

Suite 19

Boca Raton, FL 33487
